Shidqi Rifat Pangestu

rifatpangestu87@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/shidqirifatpangestu/ https://shidqirifat-portofolio.vercel.app/ https://github.com/shidqirifat

SUMMARY

I am a frontend developer with more than 1 year of experience, specializing in Tailwind CSS, Javascript, and React/Next.js. I also have some experience in fullstack web development and basic knowledge of MySQL, PHP, and Node.js. I have experience leading a team on a community project, strong critical thinking, and the ability to work effectively with teams.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Badr Interactive | June 2022 - present

Badr Interactive is a company that provides IT consulting services for client companies by assisting clients in customizing technology solutions for websites and mobile applications so as to increase business effectiveness and efficiency.

- Build web applications using Next.js framework and Tailwind CSS.
- Work closely with the backend, UI/UX, software tester, and project manager to develop features according to requirements.
- Develop and fix features according to the backlog and feedback card from PM and QA.
- Discuss with clients and team to implements features and develop it using agile and waterfall methods.
- Conduct research regarding third-party libraries to make writing code faster and more efficient.

Frontend Developer

LingoTalk | March 2022 - June 2022

PT. Intermedia Multibahasa Indonesia (LingoTalk) is an education technology solution that provides personalized language learning for schools.

- Build a frontend web according to the design using Svelte.js and integrate it into the backend.
- Conduct research on required third-party libraries and integrate their code into the project.
- Work closely with the backend and UI/UX teams to build project functions and features.
- Fix bugs, maintain code, and write reusable code for future.
- Resolved issues in the backlog, testing the code, and upload the code to the GitLab repository.

Frontend Developer Intern

Sagara Technology | December 2021 - March 2022

Sagara Technology was founded in 2014 with the mission of helping people solve critical real-world problems through digital, design, and hardware. Sagara Technology offers development web, mobile, and smart IoT services.

- Build a frontend web according to the design using Svelte.js and integrate it into the backend.
- Conduct research on required third-party libraries and integrate their code into the project.
- Work closely with the backend and UI/UX teams to build project functions and features.
- Fix bugs, maintain code, and write reusable code for future.
- Resolved issues in the backlog, testing the code, and upload the code to the GitLab repository.

SKILLS

React.js (Next.js) Redux JavaScript
Git Tailwind CSS HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Associate's Degree of Electrical Engineering

Politeknik Negeri Jakarta, 2018 - 2021

- Cumulative GPA: 3.54 / 4.00.
- Related Coursework: Electrical Circuit, Embedded System, Microcontroller, Sensor and Actuator, Database, Web, Programming Language.

LANGUAGES

English Indonesian

COURSES

- Menjadi React Web Developer Expert (2023) | Dicoding
- Menjadi Front-End Web Developer Expert (2022) | Dicoding
- Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Back-End untuk Pemula (2022) | Dicoding
- Path Pengembangan Web (Node.js) (2021) | Progate

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

Head Education and Science at KSM Psychorobotic

August 2019 - September 2020

Psychorobotic is a student study community majoring in electrical engineering that focuses on learning electronics and microcontrollers for electrical engineering students.

- Create a learning curriculum for two semesters for electrical engineering students.
- Teach students about electrical science and microcontrollers.

Project Officer at Gebyar PKM 2020

November 2019

Gebyar PKM is one of the biggest events in PNJ organized by students which aims to make students interested in PKM and find out tips on how to make a PKM proposal.

- Made training class to prepare PKM for 3 days and attended by more than 100+ people.
- Lead 18 people from 7 faculties.